# Felipe Camacho



## MSc. in Cartography & Geoinformatics (ongoing), BSc. in Geosciences

**Current Location** Olomouc, Czech Republic (Availability to relocate) **Phone** (+43) 677 64719641 - **Email** <u>f.camacho10@uniandes.edu.co</u> - **Nationality** Colombian

Geoscientist with dual master's degrees in Cartography and Geoinformatics. Over four years of professional experience in GIS, Remote Sensing, and Cartography for environmental and utilities projects in companies such as Esri and Audubon. Proficient in Esri Suite, Google Earth Engine, Adobe Suite, and programming languages, including Python, CesiumJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and SQL. Enthusiastic about time-series analysis and remote sensing applications for addressing land cover changes, performing infrastructure risk analysis, and optimizing utility services. Capable of working effectively in both team and individual settings, highly adaptable to changes, and with strong analytical skills.

## **Education**

Sep 2022 - Present (Graduation July 2024)

#### MSc, Copernicus Master in Digital Earth – Double Degree

Austria & Czech Republic

Awarded with a full scholarship for the Copernicus Master in Digital Earth, a full-time, double-degree program co-funded by the European Union.

#### Msc. in Cartography at Palacký University Olomouc (August 2023 - July 2024)

- Acquired knowledge in Cartographic Methods, Map Production and Composition, Color and Typographic Principles, and JavaScript Map Libraries (Leaflet and Mapbox). Developed proficiency in Infographics, Data Visualization, and 3D Modeling using tools like ESRI Products, Adobe Suite, Blender, and the CesiumJS library.
- **Key Courses**: Principles of Geovisualization | Thematic Cartography | Design in Geovisualization | Web Cartography | 3D Visualization
- **Projects**: Maps Portfolio | Patagonian Glaciers Monitoring Application (Google Earth Engine) | 3D Patagonian Glaciers Viewers (CesiumJS)

#### Msc. in Geoinformatics at Paris Lodron University of Salzburg (September 2022 - June 2023)

- Developed skills in Remote Sensing, Big Data, Data Analysis, Spatial Data Processing, and Spatial
  Data Infrastructures through the usage of ESRI Products, eCognition, Google Earth Engine, SQL,
  Python (GDAL, rioxarray), JavaScript (OpenLayers), HTML, and CSS.
- **Key Courses:** Remote Sensing | Big Earth Data Concepts | Spatial Statistics | SDI Services Implementation
- Projects: Snow Cover Area and Land Surface Temperature Analysis for Austria Skiing Areas with
   Google Earth Engine | ThermoSalz Web Application | Analysis of Suitable Buildings for Solar
   Panels in Salzburg | Chicago Crime Dashboard

Jan 2015 - Oct 2019

## BSc. in Geosciences at Universidad de los Andes

Bogotá, Colombia

Awarded with a full scholarship for a bachelor's degree in Geosciences.

- Acquired broad knowledge in Geoinformatics and Remote Sensing, including expertise in Drone Imagery Acquisition and Analysis, Geology, and Geochemistry. Proficient in utilizing Esri Products, Python, MATLAB, and PCI Geomatica for advanced geospatial data analyses.
- Key Courses: Remote Sensing, GIS and GPS | Computational Methods | Geology
- Projects: Multitemporal analysis of mining areas in the municipalities of Lenguazaque and Guachetá.

## **Employment History**

Mar 2023 - Jul 2023

## **Remote Sensing & GIS Intern**

Spatial Services - Salzburg, Austria

- Contributed to dwellings extraction in refugee camps for Médecins Sans Frontières (MSF), using highresolution and very high-resolution imagery with deep learning methods such as Mask R-CNN and Segment Anything by Meta AI.
- Created flood mapping algorithms within Google Earth Engine.
- Developed Geoprocessing Tools with ArcPy for Data Management.

- Created and optimized GIS workflows, Python scripts, and cartographic production methods for mapping utility infrastructures and performing disaster risk analyses.
- Modeled and analyzed potential risks for pipeline ruptures and fluid dispersion.
- Produced printed and online maps using Esri products for disaster risk response plans.

Nov 2019 - Feb 2022

## **GIS Support Analyst**

Esri Colombia – Bogotá, Colombia

- Provided high-quality technical support for Esri's English-speaking customers worldwide, focusing
  on software setup, data management, spatial analysis, cartographic products, and web application
  development.
- Resolved over 900 support cases related to ArcGIS Desktop, Pro, and Online and applications such as ArcGIS Field Maps and ArcGIS Survey123.
- Achieved an outstanding overall qualification of 4.8/5.0 from assisted clients for two years in a row.

### **Courses and Certifications**

Apr 2022 – Jun 2024 23 E-Learning Courses (SQL, Python, JavaScript, Adobe Suite)

Issued by Platzi

Oct 2021 ArcGIS Desktop Associate 19-001

Issued by Esri

Sep 2021 ArcGIS Pro Foundation 2101

Issued by Esri

Since Dec 2019 <u>126 Esri Courses Completed</u>

#### **Honors and Awards**

Sep 2022 - Present Erasmus Mundus Joint Master fully funded Scholarship

European Union

Oct 2019 BS Honor Thesis (4.83/5.00)

Universidad de Los Andes — Bogotá, Colombia

Jan 2015 – Oct 2019 Undergraduate scholarship: "Quiero Estudiar Escala"

Universidad de Los Andes - Bogotá, Colombia

## Languages

Spanish

Native

English - TOEFL iBT 107/120

Very Good (C1)

#### **Skills**

- GIS: ArcGIS (Desktop, Online, Apps, and Enterprise) and QGIS
- Earth Observation: Google Earth Engine and eCognition
- Photogrammetry: Pix4D
- Map Design and 3D Modeling: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, and Blender
- Web Development: CesiumJS, Leaflet, OpenLayers, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS
- Python packages: ArcPy, Rasterio, GDAL and Xarray.
- Databases: PostgreSQL and Microsoft SQL Server